

# **JOHN ZHAO**

Location: Los Gatos, CA 95032 | River Valley, Singapore 238307

Email: <u>zhaojohn96@gmai.com</u> Contact: 408-475-0436 Cell: 408-621-2926

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

More than 29 years of hands-on experiences in computing System, Application, Networking, Security and programming environments, lead large-scale technical projects, working with internal staff and vendors to define requirements, scope technical efforts, determine solutions, and then implement those solutions. Expert technical skills in UNIX/Linux Systems/Application build/support and development large DC on-prem/Cloud VPC integration laaS, PaaS, IaC, docker/Jenkins /k8s CI/CD/Automation with Terraform/Ansible on KVM/AWS/GCP/Azure, Python(OS/System/DB/Web Interfaces/networking/automation/data science integration, Critial data encryption/recovery, Hard-working, good team management, self-motivated, well-organized and able to work effectively under pressure on demanding environment.

#### TECHNICAL KNOWLEDGE

GitLab / GitHub / Jenkins / CI / CD/ Cloudformation /Terraform / Ansible, Kubernetes / Docker, UNIX / Linux /Windows/MacOS/WinAD-SFU, Oracle / MySQL / SQL, LDAP / KDC / NIS / IPA, SAN / NAS/Transparent Proxy, Strong Bash Shell Scripting with C/C++ / Python Package management, J2SE / J2EEApache / TLS, SQL / PL / SQL, Jumpstart / Kickstart / KVM, Grafana / Splunk /Data Dog/ Dynatrace

### **HOBBY & INTEREST**

Classical Guitar | HiFi Audio

## **ACADEMIC QUALIFICATION AND CERTIFICATION:**

- Southeast University, China B.E. Electromagnetism Field & Microwave 1986-1990
- San Diego State University, California USA B.S. Computer Science 1992-1996
- Caltech Post Graduate Program in DevOps 2022 Mar-Dec

Other: Singapore Citizen | US Green Card holder

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Sunvalley Computer Inc. (02/1999 to present) System Software Engineer Bay Area, California, United States & Singapore

- Invented Zero Trust DevOps Automation (High secure Crytocurrency level)
- System Software Engineer Lead SRE/DevOps/IT Engineering consulting for US custormer
- Unix/Linux/DB security audit, migration & data recovery over on-Prem and cloud



• C++/Python, AI, Data science, ETL/Pyspark, docker-compose, Idap/Kerberos, RestApi, Oauth on Dev & Jenkins, K8s, Java, TDV AWS, Azure DataLake, AAD, next.js,nodejs, AWS cli, terraform, ansible CI/CD on DevOps, Nagios/NRPE, Prometheus/Grafana, Splunk, Dynatrace-AppMon on Monitoring

#### Consulting supported Clients:

02/2022 – 12/2023: (contract) Principle SRE: Data platform services automation, python, data lake,terradata, Fintech securities support Finicast, Apple BI, Cigna

- Built IaC MWAA cluster (Python) on AWS Dev/Staging environment
- Built terraform/ansible/jenkins with key vault secured fintech data platform CI/CD zero trust automation
- Build Query-grid data platform on AWS & on-prem Database gateway update medical record with insurance (Jenkins -> airflow CI/CD -> Cyberark -> AWS Glue)
- Build one-trust platform develop CCPA python module for gov data security compliances

12/2015 – 03/2019: (contract) Principle DevOps: CI/CD, Cloud Infra, IAM/Direcory Services, ZFS/Cloud Storage service over 40/100gb network, Docker/PaaS support for Walmat labs, Samgsumg SSD R&D labs, Oracle Cloud US/UK region

- Built large SUN directories server farm IAM supporting 20k+ UNIX/Linux with OS PAM integration clients
- Develop docker/ZFS distributed file system with 40/100GB NIC interface as AWS cloud storage provider
- Deploy Oracle Cloud PaaS service for US/UK region

05/2004 – 09/2006: (contract) Solaris Engineer: with credit services platform deployment APAC region for DBS Vicker, Orange(French Telco), Converge Asia(Global Trading), VISA International

- Built PKI, Solaris/UNIX, application Clusters, Secure networks between Visa & banks
- Support SUN Solaris hardware/OS/network configuration, deployment & version control
- Compile & build openssh for Solaris/UNIX, OS, storage, NIS/LDAP id/group mapping, network & Application security hardening to pass Fintech compliance auditing

02/1999 – 10/2001: (contract) System Software Engineer: SUN Microsystems Inc.

 Mirgraion from Infomix/HPUX to Oracle/Solaris Platform, ProC/SCCS environment, large database application for US insurance/re-insurance Gov customer

**Kroger** (04/2019 to 02/2022)

## Sr. Software Engineer - Lead SRE/DevOps

San Jose, California, United States

- Software Development on E-commerce Tech Innovation with SDLC lead DevOps and Python Back-end Develop on GCP Gmap API services with auto-drive/delivery routing, AI/ML/Crypto market Simulation platform and tools & Azure Cloud - Application Servers, KDC, Bastion access gateway, 1Password/SSH-Key token environment. C/C++ and Python based products
- GitHub access end-to-end control, create AzureAD with web apps/api plugin, azure-identity, azure-functions, Monitoring-as-code Dynatrace, Jenkins-Master/Slave, Terraform/Ansible Dynamic inventory, Docker-compose.
- Private image compilation and service registration, initiating Datalake/Databrick backend feature, evaluating market research data automation pipeline, supporting terraform/bash/python/go/IaC/GCP/Azure cloud software & deployment related issues
- Build-in IaC K8S cluster on AWS & GKE environment for Kroger Dev/Staging environment

**HGST** (04/2011 to 11/2015) **Principal Engineer (Cloud Solution)** 



## San Jose, California, United States

- Managing IBM Professional Services on HGST support DCE/DFS and IBM AFS environment, creating Linux & AWS
  Cloud as replacement of IBM AIX legacy systems. Invented Virtual Encrypted Domain Prototype with open source
  & AD 2008 forest SSL crypto, Kerberos KDC principal
- Virtual encryted domain with Linux kernel level protection, C/C++ and Python based products
- Server bios/firmware update to match security scan & audit
- IaC based on cloudformation & terraform

Trident Microsystems Inc. (04/2008 to 03/2011) Engineering On-Premise Platform Solution

Santa Clara, California, United States

- · Creating high secured engineering design network, protecting internal IP data & repo access
- Deploy Solaris/Linux server/VM from command line & bash script automation
- Develop Xen, VM, and KVM virtualization on Intel & AMD based servers.
- Deploy Nagios monitoring tools on Solaris /Linux Enterprise level, IaC based on Jumpstart & Kickstart
- built Liunx kernel level security for data security, C/C++ and Python based products

FormFactor Inc. (07/2006 to 03/2008)

Systems Analyst (On-Premise ERP Application)

Livermore, California, United States

Providing supervision, administers all aspects of an advanced, ERP/Oracle RAC system build & supporting a
specifiedfunctional area on Solaris/Linux/VMS/UNIX/ESX/Container/LDOM infrastructure environment, plan and
coordinate system utilization, and perform growth analysis and capacity planning, perform systems and
applications analysis/design and programming to produce a variety of innovative solutions to complex problems,
perform installation, maintenance, training, and user support as required; plans and coordinates projects to meet
future needs.

Advanced Network Technology Laboratories Pte Ltd (11/2001 to 05/2004) Regional Tech Support (Linux networking & security product after sales) Singapore

- APAC regional technical support for ISP customer (Linux based networking & security product)
- Server/storage/network/security integration firmware update & support

**Ascom Technologies** (06/1995 to 02/1999) **Tech Support (Singapore Gov Computing Solution Provider)**Singapore

- Singapore Gov Computing Solution Provider (Software from UK, Mainfrain Hardware from USA)
- Server/storage/network parts plan & integration
- ProC, UNIX/HP-UX/Solaris systems, security & databases services

**REFERENCE** (Available on request)



https://www.linkedin.com/in/john-j-zhao-8656698/

 $https://github.com/johnjzhao/lab/blob/main/DOC/Coding\_Certificate\_JZ.pdf$